Privacy Policy
==============

Last updated: February 13, 2024

This privacy policy explains how, why and under what conditions the Open Terms Archive (OTA) site collects personal information and how it is used. Our privacy policy will change over time. And of course, we [publicly record those changes](https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/demo-versions/commits/main/Open%20Terms%20Archive/Privacy%20Policy.md) with Open Terms Archive 😉

Personal data processed
-----------------------

When you subscribe to the document change tracking service, we collect your email address. This allows us to notify you when a modification is detected on the document you have selected.  
This email is stored in a Brevo list ([https://brevo.com](https://brevo.com/)).

In accordance with Article 17 of the GDPR, everyone has the right to have their data erased. Users of this service whose personal data has been collected may request the deletion of such data by writing to the dedicated address: [contact@opentermsarchive.org](mailto:contact@opentermsarchive.org)

The person responsible for processing the data is Henri Verdier, french Ambassador for Digital Affairs.

Conservation
------------

The data will be kept for a maximum of 5 years from the last email sent, and archived according to the legal statute of limitations (5 years), unless Open Terms Archive has a legal obligation to do so.

Cookies deposited and opt-out
-----------------------------

When you visit this website, we leave a small text file (a “cookie”) on your computer. This allows us to measure how many visits we’ve had and which pages are most viewed.

### Why doesn’t this website show a consent banner for cookies?

The tracking software we use, Matomo, is open-source, self-managed, and set up to properly anonymize your data and is thus exempt from prior consent according to the French data protection authority CNIL’s recommendations.

I contribute to your data, can I access it?
-------------------------------------------

Of course! The analytics data for this website are publicly available on [stats.data.gouv.fr](https://stats.data.gouv.fr/index.php?module=CoreHome&action=index&idSite=179&period=range&date=previous30&updated=1#?idSite=179&period=range&date=previous30&segment=&category=Dashboard_Dashboard&subcategory=1)
